<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Harpreet Singh</title>
    <link>https://harpreet287.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Harpreet Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 18:48:45 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://harpreet287.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://harpreet287.github.io/docs/first_one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 18:48:45 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://harpreet287.github.io/docs/first_one/</guid>
      <description>Greetings! 👋 # Introduction # Greetings, I&amp;rsquo;m Harpreet Singh, a Computer Science major at IIITH, finished my third semester. Having recently completed courses like CS3.301 (Operating Systems and Networks) and CS1.302 (Automata Theory), I find myself intrigued by the practical applications of Computer Science. Witnessing theories come to life in computer systems and algorithms has been truly captivating.&#xA;What to Expect. # As someone with dynamic interests, my focus shifts based on current happenings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>371. Sum of Two Integers</title>
      <link>https://harpreet287.github.io/docs/lc/getsum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://harpreet287.github.io/docs/lc/getsum/</guid>
      <description>Leetcode 371 # Sum of Two Integers # Problem Statement:&#xA;Given two integers a and b, return the sum of the two integers without using the operators + and -.&#xA;Logic # We would be treating a and b in binary form for understanding bit operations. First bit of sum calculated by xor(0^1, 1^0, 0^0, 1^1), but for the addition such as 1+1 = 10 we must have some carry, which can be found by &amp;amp; operator between the two numbers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8. String to Integer</title>
      <link>https://harpreet287.github.io/docs/lc/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://harpreet287.github.io/docs/lc/8/</guid>
      <description>8. String to Integer # Problem Statement # Implement the myAtoi(string s) function, which converts a string to a 32-bit signed integer (similar to C/C++&amp;#39;s atoi function). The algorithm for myAtoi(string s) is as follows: Read in and ignore any leading whitespace. Check if the next character (if not already at the end of the string) is &amp;#39;-&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;+&amp;#39;. Read this character in if it is either. This determines if the final result is negative or positive respectively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rating Algorithm in chess</title>
      <link>https://harpreet287.github.io/docs/wa/rating_system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://harpreet287.github.io/docs/wa/rating_system/</guid>
      <description>Chess rating system # Introduction # A chess rating system is a system used in chess to estimate the strength of a player, based on their performance versus other players. They are used by organisations like FIDE, English Chess Federation and online chess websites like chess.com, Lichess only to name a few. In general for a player, their strength is determined by the rating, higher rating indicates more proficiency.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
